hello what is up everybody Welcome to
The Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski on this podcast we talk
about ways that coaches trainers and
mentors can grow and scale their
business successfully online and
strategies both for your mindset as well
as practical ways and so let's dive into
that right now today I want to talk
about something that has been affecting
me I find it affects my clients often
and it's this
notion that you know everything that we
do needs to be up to a certain standard
that other people expect of us and that
the opinions of other people sway us to
and fro constantly let me just give you
an example of this you know I made a
post on social media the other day that
I think was very valuable and I got a
feedback from it that the person
believed that they found the biggest
scammer in the entire industry that I
that I Jeremiah Kowski am the biggest
scammer that exist exists in the entire
coaching
industry what I said is that you're
selling the promise not just necessarily
your methodology that the hook that you
use to actually Market to people has
nothing to do with your track record
what you know what you understand it has
everything to do with your ability to
sell persuade and frame it in a way that
people desire okay now what you're doing
is you want to frame something in your
offer that is the answer to everything
they've been praying for that leads them
to the framework that you sell that is
what produces positive
results and so somebody said that well
that defines me as a scammer I've gotten
negative feedback from from people for
years about what I do in business that I
should stop that I should stay in my
Lane that I should stop doing what I'm
doing that I'm not qualified enough the
list goes on and it used to bother me it
used to get in my head you can't let it
get in your head you can't let it bother
you you can't let it affect you when
people get angry with you get upset with
you write you nasty letters telling you
how horrible you are I'm I'm
serious and some of you might say well
no I would never experience that cuz I
would just do everything right and they
would never do that that's that's cute
that maybe you think that uh you can
never do anything right enough to a
avoid people being that way because that
is a human thing that crazy people will
do especially the coaches and mentors is
they will find their self- validation
for their own insecurities by putting
you down by being negative no matter how
much Integrity you have and so realize
that it's best to go out there and just
do whatever you want to do that feels
best to you and stop being afraid of
what other people think about you and
how they're going to judge you and what
they might misjudge about you as far as
this goes this is one of the biggest
areas that I find that a lot of
beginning coaches and mentors a lot of
people even in my coaching group deal
with is they're so cautious and careful
to make sure that they do everything
right by everybody around them so that
nobody can say anything negative about
them and I'm sorry but that is
impossible you could never do anything
right enough in this business of
coaching training and mentoring and even
as a saying this some of you are either
getting triggered you're disagreeing
you're angry that I'm even saying this
or you're
scared understand that all of those
emotions are
normal and realize that I'm here saying
something that you're probably not going
to hear on on most podcast is that you
are going to piss people off when you
start to reach a certain level of
success in your business all of my
clients tell me that once they start
actually making an impact with their
webinars and they started attracting
more people they get very negative nasty
feedback from people about just how
disappointed and upset people are in in
in the lack of like whatever they did
that they expected and that the person
didn't fulfill it for
them and you can't let that get in your
head or it will get in your head this is
an area that I've had to work on with my
therapist I'm still working on I'm still
even struggling in this area sometimes
I'm not coming to you today as somebody
who has it all together I'm coming to
you today as somebody and even by me
saying that some of you some people
believe well if you don't have it all
together then you got no right to talk
on that topic that's
Insanity to me it's
insane that we have a culture that tries
to silence people that would try to
silence me from telling you the truth
because it's something that I'm still
working through myself isn't that nuts
and yet that is the society that we live
in today that has these
religious Academia
based rigid standards of
perfection that it forces on
people and that if you don't fall in
line with all of those standards of
perfection well you're
trash and you might as well just not
even do anything and that's what Society
will try to beat into your head we'll
try to tell you we'll try to convince
you truth is you're not going to please
everybody you're not going to make
everybody
happy focus in on the ones who love you
who love your content who love how
you're connecting with them and stop
worrying about trying to get the ones
who don't to be convinced about
you they're not even convinced
themselves about themselves and that's
why they got to rip you down and so
understand that and don't make it be
this thing I see it happen so often this
it makes me sad great coaches that with
a great message stay silent and don't
grow their business because they think
that they're not good enough while less
skilled coaches make
millions because they are willing to put
themselves out there and not worry about
what other people think about them it's
incredible to me
and I and I think that if you're
listening to this right now you might
fall into that category that you might
be somebody who's greatly skilled who
has a great message to share with
people and yet you let the opinions or
potential opinions that you're trying to
avoid happening from other people stop
you from putting yourself out there we
cannot let what might not go our way
quote unquote somebody being super
negative about you and ripping into you
and saying that you're not not qualified
and you should just quit your business
that's not something anybody wants
somebody to tell
them and yet trying to avoid and control
people so they don't say those things to
us is literally a recipe for total
disaster and will stop you from being
successful in your business and so if
you are a coach you're a mentor you're a
trainer and you want to be successful
you're going to have to work through not
letting people and what they say and
what they demand and their expectations
and their disappointment be tools of
manipulation to make you change your
personality your message and how you
show up and you trying to be so perfect
by everybody's requirements of
you you'll go nuts if you try to do that
I've tried trust me how do I I'm talking
from experience I have
tried and it made me feel like I was
going nuts it's not
possible to make everybody be your
biggest fan it's just
not and so in this business in the
coaching business if you want to make
money focus in on the people that you
can help the most ignore the ones who
are the haters stop trying to convince
people that dislike you that don't like
how the way you do things that think
that you're not good enough have a
foothold on your brain and your
decisionmaking
process I had people for years come to
me and tell me that I had no right to
ever think that I could coach
somebody and that it
was appalling that I even thought that I
had anything of value to share with
people and that it
was disgusting to them even seeing me
try I had people come to me and tell me
that constantly for a long time and yet
I still continued resiliently no matter
what anybody said was it hard of course
having people come to you and tell you
that not only should you stop but that
you disgust
them it's
hard absolutely
is every time that I suffered I
submitted to the version of my life that
they wanted me to live to the version of
how I should be coaching people to the
version of how they thought that I
should be building my
business and it led to suffering for me
and anytime that I've thrived I threw
all of that out the window said I do not
care what any of them say I'm going to
do what I want to
do because I know that that I'm called
to do this and it excites me and I know
that I can help people am I perfect at
it no of course not I fail all the
time but I'm getting better I'm
improving I have people to this day they
write me emails telling me how horrible
of a coach I
am how just appalled they are that I
think that I have anything to share with
you they I still get those
emails doesn't stop me last year we
built a multi-million dollar business
and so realize that no matter what track
record you have people will still do
that no matter how much results you've
produced people will still do
that see I meet a lot of people they're
trying to avoid that from happening
they're trying to avoid people from
thinking those things about them and
saying them they're going to say it no
matter what they're going to say it no
matter what you you've done or will
do so why are you wasting your time
trying to avoid a possible fictional
scenario that is only going to end up
eventually happening anyways when you
gain
traction it's like this crazy
Mindbender that I see people hold them
back from marketing their business
powerfully
because they they they don't don't want
people to be disappointed in them they
don't want people to be upset with them
they don't want people to be angry with
them you will not ever be able to do
everything right
enough ever by some people because some
people just get their kicks off in
kicking other people down no matter how
great you are and so own your greatness
step into your greatness and stop trying
to manage what other people say or think
about you you're never going to please
everybody but you will make a ton of
money in your business when you stop
worrying about what they
think absolutely I believe that you can
be successful as a coach and as a mentor
you do
not need to be the world's greatest
success to finally be qualified enough
to put yourself out there you just need
to know a little bit more than somebody
else about a specific
topic and help lead somebody to that
result period And I guarantee you if
you've been on planet Earth for more
than 25 years literally some people say
that if you're 25 you got no right to
coach gosh people told me that for five
years when I was 30 they're like you're
too young to coach I'm like shut up
literally shut not something that I am
going to change what I'm doing and how
I'm building my business and where I'm
going not going to but I let it stop me
for a long time and I let it prevent me
from putting myself out there I didn't
launch my program because I was
terrified of those people guess what
they just got worse when I launched
everything it's true nothing nothing's
ever going to change
that I've just had to learn to literally
not
give any care or heed to such feedback
feedback is great I love getting
feedback but there is a type of feedback
that is dark
criticism the I guess that's how I would
describe it it's a very like it's very
dark negative like almost like it's kind
of like chokes you out a little
bit and I have no tolerance for that I
know I won't be rude to the person I'm
not even going to I mean generally I'm
not going to I'm not going to uh tell
them off it's not my personality to do
that but I will gladly ignore them and
not communicate with them or try to
convince them or make a connection I'm
not trying to connect with that person I
got something else going on in their
life it's not my job to change that so
all right so I want this to encourage
you no matter what stage you're at I
meet so many coaches trainers and
mentors and they tell me I feel like I'm
not good enough I feel like I'm not good
enough
yet to be able to put my stuff out there
to be able to make the kind of money
that I want to make and
it's it's
sad
that people feel that way it's
that they might have 40 years experience
mentoring people but because they don't
have the perfect testimony they hold
themselves back
that's a choice and that's a mindset
issue more than a strategy
issue anybody can learn to sell anybody
can learn to be persuasive but if you
hold yourself back because of others
opinions because you're trying to
self-protect or you justify it under
being a a spirit of
Excellence that's another side of it
could be haughtiness could be Pride that
you're dealing with could be that you
won't lower yourself to that level
of whatever and that you feel
self-righteous and better than everybody
else because you're not going to do that
oh my gosh that's even
worse that's a whole other
topic we talk about that in another
episode I find both end up stopping
people haughtiness self-righteousness
Pride or worry and fear that
people are going to hurt them are going
to dislike them are going to be
disappointed you might have a PR you
might have a pride
issue in the fact that you don't
disappoint people a self-righteous Heir
about you that you always please
everybody gosh I've met coaches that
have that one they argue with me on this
topic that I'm talking about they they
get very angry about what I've just
shared and
yet are they making seven figures in
their business no they're not
I don't mean that to be arrogant at all
but I wouldn't want to make as much
money as they are I'm much happier with
my bank roll than somebody who thinks
the way that these dark critics think
these hecklers
these people who
always have a reason in an opinion why
you shouldn't be doing the things that
you're
doing they come out of the would work
every month for me when I'm marketing my
business especially when you go out
there in
public
constantly they send me Bullet bulleted
lists as to all the things I did wrong
by them in my training and that Jeremiah
if you just fix these you'd actually
make some
money if you just fix these you'd
actually be a legit coach
goodness and do I consider some of that
feedback
sure but nine times out of 10 I've
considered
it and listen I've been in this business
for 20 years I'm at the point now like
it is very rare that I get feedback that
like makes me change anything now
because people haven't seen seen what
I've seen they haven't gone through what
I've gone through they don't have my
story so learn from me you don't need to
arrive quote unquote by the way I've not
arrived you don't need to reach some
level of success to finally earn the
right to be able to do this you can do
this from day one and I would recommend
you do do this from day
one
absolutely had somebody last night
telling me Jeremiah
gosh you're encouraged enaging people
who can't produce results for their
clients to Market their
business I'm encouraging people who are
beginners to get better at their craft
instead of holding back because of some
arbitrary gatekeeper that tells them
that they're not good enough until they
jump through 10
hoops and I will always be a voice for
that all
right I believe that coaches Chang the
world mentors change the
world your business can change the world
your business can improve people's lives
and make their lives
better you can make a whole ton of a
money doing so whole bunch of money
doing
so but we got to stop worrying what
everybody thinks about
us you will make way more money that way
all right everybody grow your life if
this has helped you share it with
somebody
if you hate me write me some hate mail I
don't care we'll talk soon have a good
[Music]
[Applause]
one